imagine two cubes one with a side length
a and one with a side length B the
number a cubed plus B Cubed is given by
the volume of these two cubes let's add
an A plus b by a by B rectangular prism
to this diagram which encloses a volume
of a plus b times a times B now we can
decompose this region into two different
cuboids one of them the shorter and
deeper green one shown can be rotated
and shifted as pictured notice that
these two cuboids sit inside an A plus b
outer shell and if we look at the top of
this diagram we see an a by a square and
a b by B squared so the area is a
squared plus b squared therefore the
volume of these two shapes is a plus b
times a squared plus b squared but now
we can reshift the cuboids together and
remove the region that we originally
added by subtracting that from both
sides of the equation therefore a cubed
plus B Cubed is equal to a plus b times
a squared plus b squared minus a times B